
<!--
Copyright (c) 2000-2003, Jim Crafton
All rights reserved.
Redistribution and use in source and binary forms, with or without
modification, are permitted provided that the following conditions
are met:
	Redistributions of source code must retain the above copyright
	notice, this list of conditions and the following disclaimer.

	Redistributions in binary form must reproduce the above copyright
	notice, this list of conditions and the following disclaimer in 
	the documentation and/or other materials provided with the distribution.

THIS SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED BY THE COPYRIGHT HOLDERS AND CONTRIBUTORS "AS IS" 
AND ANY EXPRESS OR IMPLIED WARRANTIES, INCLUDING, BUT NOT
LIMITED TO, THE IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY AND FITNESS FOR
A PARTICULAR PURPOSE ARE DISCLAIMED.  IN NO EVENT SHALL THE REGENTS
OR CONTRIBUTORS BE LIABLE FOR ANY DIRECT, INDIRECT, INCIDENTAL, SPECIAL,
EXEMPLARY, OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES (INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO,
PROCUREMENT OF SUBSTITUTE GOODS OR SERVICES; LOSS OF USE, DATA, OR
PROFITS; OR BUSINESS INTERRUPTION) HOWEVER CAUSED AND ON ANY THEORY OF
LIABILITY, WHETHER IN CONTRACT, STRICT LIABILITY, OR TORT (INCLUDING
NEGLIGENCE OR OTHERWISE) ARISING IN ANY WAY OUT OF THE USE OF THIS 
SOFTWARE, EVEN IF ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH DAMAGE.

NB: This software will not save the world.

-->

<section id="GraphicsKit"><title>GraphicsKit</title>
	<para>
	The GraphicsKit is a library dedicated to graphics related classes and 
	functionality. It contains classes for drawing vector shapes, rendering
	images, drawing text, drawing to an external printer, support for images,
	and a simple plug-in system for adding image file formats to support
	additional image file formats. The default image support is for PNG 
	and JPEG files.
	</para>
	<para>
	The GraphicsKit needs to be initialized at your program's startup, and it 
	needs to be closed down, or terminated, when your program exits. Because the
	GraphicsKit builds on the FoundationKit, it automatically initializes the
	FoudantionKit, and terminates the FoundationKit for you. Proper 
	initialization/termination of the GraphicsKit looks something like this:
	<programlisting><![CDATA[
int main( int argc, char** argv ) 
{
	VCF::GraphicsKit::init( argc, argv ); //FoundationKit automatically initialized 
	
	//your code here....
	
	VCF::GraphicsKit::terminate(); //FoundationKit automatically terminated 
	return 0;
}
	]]></programlisting>
	Improper usage would be:
	<programlisting><![CDATA[
int main( int argc, char** argv ) 
{
	VCF::FoundationKit::init( argc, argv );// BAD!!!!
	VCF::GraphicsKit::init( argc, argv ); 
	
	//your code here....
	
	VCF::GraphicsKit::terminate(); 
	VCF::FoundationKit::terminate();// BAD!!!!
	return 0;
}
	]]></programlisting>
	This will result in all sorts of problems - just don't go there.
	</para>
	
	<section id="GraphicsContext"><title>The GraphicsContext</title>
		<para>
		The GraphicsContext is the basic class you will use in the GraphicsKit. It's 
		where you do all your drawing, even if you're working with images (unless
		you're manipulating the pixels directly).
		</para>
	</section>
	
	<section id="GraphicsToolkit"><title>The GraphicsToolkit</title>
		<para>
		The GraphicsToolkit is used to create various instances of peer classes,
		to create images, and several other utility functions, like getting 
		the color from a system color constant.
		</para>
		<para>
		The GraphicsToolkit is a singleton, and access to it is implemented as a 
		series of static functions. Unless you are porting the VCF to a new platform
		you do not need direct access to the GraphicsToolkit singleton itself.
		</para>
		
		<para>
		You can create images using the GraphicsToolkit by calling 
		the GraphicsToolkit::createImage() functions. You can create a blank image
		from a width and height, an image that copies it's data from an existing
		GraphicsContext, or an image that is loaded from a file. For example:
		<programlisting> <![CDATA[
Image* image1 = GraphicsToolkit::createImage( 100, 400 ); //create an image 100 X 400 pixels in dimension
Image* image2 = GraphicsToolkit::createImage( "C:\Stuff\More Stuff\Images\Whoops.jpg" ); //loads the image "Whoops.jpg" from disk
		]]></programlisting>
		The above example creates "image1" by specifying pixel dimensions, and "image2"
		is created by specifying a file name. See 
		</para>
	</section>
	
	<section id="GK_Colors"><title>Colors</title>
		<para>
		The GraphicsKit has a special class that deals with assigning and 
		converting color's called, astonishingly enough, Color. Internally all 
		color data is stored as red, green and blue components, with each component 
		stored in a double, within the	range 0.0 to 1.0. The next release of the 
		VCF will probably add a fourth component to store the alpha value (also 
		between 0.0 and 1.0) of the color. Yo can initialize the color instance
		in a number of ways:
		<programlisting><![CDATA[
Color color1( 1.0, 0.0, 0.0 ); //color red
Color color2( "blue" ); //color blue
Color color3( 0x00, 0xFF, 0x00 ); //green
Color color4( 0.5, 1.0, 1.0, ctHSV ); //should be lite blue (equivalent to #00FFFF)
		]]></programlisting>
		</para>
		<para>
		There are a wide variety of functions to convert between different color 
		spaces, such as HSV, HLS, RGB, Yuv, and CMYK. The individual components 
		of the color may be modified, or you can change things more "holistically"
		by changing the luminance or hue of the color. For example:
		<programlisting><![CDATA[
Color color("blue");
color.setLuminosity( 123 );
		]]></programlisting>
		</para>
	</section>
	
	<section id="GK_Images"><title>Images</title>
		<para>
		An Image represents the neccessary data to display a graphic on a 
		GraphicsContext. You can draw an Image on a GraphicsContext by calling the 
		GraphicsContext::drawImage() method and passing in the Image instance.
		</para>
		<para>
		An Image has a height and width, describing it's dimensions in pixels. It 
		provides access to it's pixel data through pointer to the pixel memory buffer.
		Each Image also has an internal GraphicsContext associated with it. Any 
		drawing on the Image's GraphicsContext is reflected in the Image's pixel data.
		</para>
		<para>
		Each pixel is composed of 4 color channels (red, green, blue, and an alpha chanel). 
		The precise	layout of the channels in memory is dependent on the system you 
		are running on. For example in Win32, the layout is blue, green, red, alpha. On 
		a linux machine (x86 architecture) the layout is read, green, blue, alpha. The 
		data size for each channel may vary from 8 to 32 bits. The default is 8 bits. The 
		Image has a descriptor member that defines what the channel depth is, whether it 
		is floating point, or integer based, and the layout order. 
		</para>
		<para>
		To actually get at the pixel data that makes up the Image class you get an pointer 
		to the ImageBits class. This class is responsible for actually holding the raw bits 
		that make up the image. This class is a template class that can be specialized 
		for various kinds of data and pixel layout order. The default specialization is 
		dependant on the platform you compile the VCF for. At a later date you'll be able 
		to create Images of any arbitrary pixel depth. To get the raw pixel data you call 
		the ImageBits's getData() method which returns a pointer to the pixel buffer. This 
		buffer is seen as a unsigned char*.
		</para>
		<para>
		To work with pixel data in a neutral fashion use the RGBAVals structure. It 
		represents a single pixel worth of image data. 
		<programlisting>
		<![CDATA[
Image* image = //...get an image from somewhere

RGBAVals* pixels = image->getPixels();
for ( ulong32 y=0;y<image->getHeight() ) {
	for ( ulong32 x=0;x<image->getWidth() ) {
		//modify only blue values
		pixels[ y * image->getWidth() + x ].b += 20;
	}
} 
		]]>
		</programlisting>
		Value ranges for color channels that are integer based are 0 to 2<superscript>
		channel depth</superscript> .
		Value ranges for color channels that are floating point based are 0.0 to 1.0.
		</para>
	</section>

	<section id="GK_Fonts"><title>Fonts</title>
		<para>
		A Font object is a representation of a set of functions and data used to
		render a string onto GraphicsContext. Fonts may be bitmap/raster based,
		vector, TrueType, OpenType, or Post Script. The exact type largely depends 
		on the system that the VCF is running on.
		</para>
		<para>
		For international characters, the actually handling of rendering is done 
		by the low level system calls, and is largely (if not completely) transparent
		to a user of the VCF.
		<note>
			<para>
			In the future this may change, but for now it is handled by the peer
			implementation of either the FontPeer, ContextPeer or both working together,
			depending on the system.
			</para>
			<para>
			For Win32 this is handled via the Win32 API, for linux (using GTK2) this 
			is handled via the 
			<ulink url="http://developer.gnome.org/doc/API/2.0/pango/">Pango</ulink> API.
			</para>
		</note>
		</para>
		<para>
		For international text that needs to handle bi-directional text from 
		different character sets, for example a chunk of text in English (flowing from 
		left to right) mixed with some text in Hebrew (flowing from right to left),
		there may be issues if this is not handled correctly by the low level 
		graphics implementation. The public VCF API's do not currently address this.
		</para>
		<para>
		A Font can be changed at any time during the instances lifetime. You can change 
		the size (either specifying pixel size or point size), the font name (such as 
		"Times New Roman"), various attributes, like bold, italic, or strike out, and 
		the color to use when rendering the font.
		</para>
		<para>
		A Font consists of a number of attributes, such as name, size, style (bold, 
		italic, et al), ascent, descent, and height. Some of these attributes are 
		read-only, providing information about the dimensions of the font, and others
		can be changed at will. The following table illustrates this:
		<table frame="none" pgwide="1">
			<tgroup cols="2" align="left" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
				<thead>
					<row>
						<entry>Attribute name</entry>
						<entry>Read-only</entry>						
					</row>							
				</thead>
				<tbody>
					<row>
						<entry>Name</entry>
						<entry>No</entry>
					</row>
					<row>
						<entry>Size</entry>
						<entry>No</entry>
					</row>
					<row>
						<entry>Bold</entry>
						<entry>No</entry>
					</row>

					<row>
						<entry>Italic</entry>
						<entry>No</entry>
					</row>

					<row>
						<entry>Strikeout</entry>
						<entry>No</entry>
					</row>
					<row>
						<entry>Underlined</entry>
						<entry>No</entry>
					</row>
					<row>
						<entry>Color</entry>
						<entry>No</entry>
					</row>
					<row>
						<entry>Shear</entry>
						<entry>No</entry>
					</row>
					<row>
						<entry>Angle</entry>
						<entry>No</entry>
					</row>
					<row>
						<entry>Ascent</entry>
						<entry>Yes</entry>
					</row>
					<row>
						<entry>Descent</entry>
						<entry>Yes</entry>
					</row>
					<row>
						<entry>External Leading</entry>
						<entry>Yes</entry>
					</row>
					<row>
						<entry>Internal Leading</entry>
						<entry>Yes</entry>
					</row>
					<row>
						<entry>Height</entry>
						<entry>Yes</entry>
					</row>
				</tbody>
			</tgroup>
		</table>
		<note>
			<para>
			Anything that is <emphasis>not</emphasis> marked read-only
			can be changed.
			</para>
		</note>
		</para>
		<para>
		To use a font, simple create it on the heap or stack. To change attributes,
		call any of the setXXX methods. To use it with a GraphicsContext, call the 
		GraphicsContext::setCurrentFont() method. This will <emphasis>copy</emphasis>
		hte font's information into the GraphicsContext's member font. All text functions
		will then use that font for drawing text till the font is changed.
		<programlisting><![CDATA[
GraphicsContext* gc = getSomeGraphicsContext();//some function to get a GraphicsContext

Font myFont;
myFont.setName( "Times New Roman" );
myFont.setPixelSize( 20 );

gc->setCurrentFont( &amp;myFont );
gc->textAt( 12, 300, "Hello!" );

Font* myFont = new Font("Arial");
myFont->setColor( &amp;Color(1.0, 0.0, 0.0) ); //changes the color to red
myFont->setItalic( true );

gc->setCurrentFont( myFont );
myFont->free();//destroy our font - we don't need it anymore

gc->textAt( 12, 375, "Hello2!" );
		]]></programlisting>
		</para>		
	</section>
	<section id="GK_Paths"><title>Paths</title>
		<para>
		Paths represent a series of 1 or more points. The points can form a closed shape 
		or polygon, like a circle, or rectangle, or an open shape like a line. A Path is 
		"closed" if it has more than one point and it's end point is equal to it's starting 
		point. The Path class represents an interface, and you cannot create instances of 
		it directly. Instead you need to create instances of classes that implement the
		Path interface.
		</para>
		<para>
		A Path itself is not drawn. Instead you "stroke" or "fill" the path with an 
		imaginary brush that paints on the GraphicsContext. The various sub classes of the 
		Stroke and Fill classes are responsible for doing the actual painting, see the
		<link linkend="GK_Strokes">Strokes</link> and <link linkend="GK_Fills">Fills</link> 
		sections for more information.
		</para>
		<para>
		A Path may be transformed, using matrix math and a 3X3 matrix. Basic transformations 
		include scaling, rotating, shearing, and translation. Transforms are performed using the
		Matrix2D class which holds the tranform matrix data. 
		</para>		
		<para>
		The basic Path implementation is the BezierCurve class. It allows you to create
		lines, rectangles, curves, and so on. In the future more sophisticated classes may be added,
		and developers are free to add their own implementations if they want. Here's an example
		of using a path:
		<programlisting><![CDATA[		
BezierCurve shape;
shape.moveTo( 100, 100 );
shape.lineTo( 300, 300 );
shape.lineTo( 500, 300 );
		]]></programlisting>
		The above draws 2 lines. You can render, or paint, the Path by calling the 
		GraphicsContext::draw() function and passing in the path.
		<programlisting><![CDATA[		
GraphicsContext* ctx = ...
ctx->draw( &shape ); //paints the path
		]]></programlisting>
		You can transform the path quite easily:
		<programlisting><![CDATA[		
Matrix2D translate;
translate.translate( -125, -400 );
Matrix2D rotate;
rotate.rotate( 45 );

Matrix2D mat;
mat.multiply( &translate, &rotate );

BezierCurve rect;
rect.rectangle( Rect(75,350,175,450) );
rect.applyTransform( translate );

		]]></programlisting>
		<note>
		Each transform operation on a Matrix2D instance resets the matrix data.
		If you first called Matrix2D::translate(), then called Matrix2D::rotate(), the 
		previous data in the matrices for the translate call would be erased.
		</note>
		</para>
	</section>	
	
	<section id="GK_Transforms"><title>Transforms</title>
		<para>
		Transforms in the VCF are implemented as affine transformations, using a 3 X 3 matrix
		of doubles. These are stored in the Matrix2D class, which also provides a series of methods 
		for altering the matrix. The matrix can be applied to any kind of drawing that is performed
		on the GraphicsContext.
		</para>
		<para>
		Tha Matrix2D class allows you specify translate, scale, shear (or skew), and 
		rotate values. It also has the ability to invert itself, and to multiply matrices 
		together. Any time the Matrix2D functions for translation, scaling, shearing, 
		or rotation are called, the previous data in the matrix is lost, and replaced with 
		an identity set. 
		</para>		
		<para>
		The GraphicsContext maintains a tranform matrix in it's graphics state. This 
		matrix is used to transform coordinates for any vector drawing and image
		drawing that happen after the matrix is changed. The GraphicsContext transform
		can be manipulated by calling the GraphicsContext::setCurrentTransform(),
		GraphicsContext::setRotation(), GraphicsContext::setTranslation(), 
		GraphicsContext::setShear(), or GraphicsContext::setScale(). While GraphicsContext::setCurrentTransform()
		replaces the entire transform, the other functions set a specific value in the graphics
		state, and then all the various transform values (rotation, scaling, shearing,
		and translation) are then concatenated, or multiplied, together to form the 
		current transform matrix. If you have a specific series of values that you want
		multiplied together in a specific order, then you should do so using your own
		Matrix2D instance, and then set the whole transform at once, and not call
		the individual setXXX methods of the GraphicsContext.
		</para>
	</section>
	
	<section id="GK_Strokes"><title>Strokes</title>
		<para>
		The Stroke class is use to paint a "stroke" or outline along a 
		<link linkend="GK_Paths">Path</link>. The GraphicsContext graphics state 
		has a current stroke, which points to some instance of a Stroke class
		or NULL, which is it's intial value . You don't create instance of the 
		Stroke class directly, it's an interface. Instead you create an instance 
		of classes that derive from and implement the Stroke interface. Strokes 
		may or may not support anti-aliasing, though with the presence of the 
		<ulink url="">AGG library</ulink> in the VCF, developers of Stroke 
		classes are encouraged to use it to provide anti-aliased support.
		</para>
		<para>
		A Stroke is used only when the GraphicsContext::draw() function is called
		and passed a Path instance. This triggers the context to use the current 
		Stroke. If the current Stroke is NULL, then no outline will be painted for 
		the path. No other primitive functions, like GraphicsContext::moveTo(),
		GraphicsContext::lineTo(), GraphicsContext::rectangle(), etc make use of 
		the graphics states current Stroke (or Fill) instances. 
		</para>
		<section id="Stroke_Usage"><title>Usage</title>
		<para>
		The stroke can be changed on a GraphicsContext by calling the 
		GraphicsContext::setCurrentStroke() function, and passing a pointer
		to a Stroke instance. Keep in mind that the GraphicsContext does 
		<emphasis>not</emphasis> retain the pointer, instead it's the caller's 
		responsibility to free memory when they are through with the Stroke.
		It's also a good idea to reset the GraphicsContext's stroke to 
		NULL when you've deleted your Stroke instance. It's perfectably 
		acceptable to have Stroke instances allocated on the stack instead
		of using the heap. 
		</para>
		<para>
		The default stroke implementation provided is the BasicStroke class. It 
		supports anti-aliased rendering through AGG, and has several other
		settings that can be modified, such as the opacity, dashing, color,
		and width. 
		<note>
		Some settings only take effect if the drawing is taking place on a 
		GraphicsContext	that has anti-aliasing turned on.
		</note>
		Here's a simple example:
		<programlisting><![CDATA[
GraphicsContext* ctx = ....
BasicStroke bs;
bs.setWidth( 3 );
ctx->setCurrentStroke( &bs );
BezierCurve shape;
shape.moveTo( 100, 100 );
shape.lineTo( 300, 300 );
shape.lineTo( 500, 300 );
ctx->draw( &shape );
ctx->setCurrentStroke( NULL );
		]]></programlisting>
		
		</para>
		</section>
		<section id="Stroke_Impl"><title>Implementation</title>
		<para>
		There are no set rules for how to implement the Stroke interface.
		The primary function to implement is the Stroke::render() function
		which will pass the stroke a Path instance. The Path will already 
		have been transformed by the GraphicsContext's transform matrix.
		</para>
		</section>		
	</section>
	
	<section id="GK_Fills"><title>Fills</title>
		<para>
		The Fill class is use to fill in the area in between a 
		<link linkend="GK_Paths">Path</link>. The GraphicsContext graphics state 
		has a current fill, which points to some instance of a Fill class
		or NULL, which is it's intial value . You don't create instance of the 
		Fill class directly, it's an interface. Instead you create an instance 
		of classes that derive from and implement the Fill interface. Fills 
		may or may not support anti-aliasing, though with the presence of the 
		<ulink url="">AGG library</ulink> in the VCF, developers of Fill 
		classes are encouraged to use it to provide anti-aliased support.
		</para>
		<para>
		A Fill is used only when the GraphicsContext::draw() function is called
		and passed a Path instance. This triggers the context to use the current 
		fill. If the current fill is NULL, then the path will not be filled. No 
		other primitive functions, like GraphicsContext::moveTo(), 
		GraphicsContext::lineTo(), GraphicsContext::rectangle(), etc make use of 
		the graphics states current Fill (or Stroke) instances. 
		</para>
		<section id="Fill_Usage"><title>Usage</title>
		<para>
		The fill can be changed on a GraphicsContext by calling the 
		GraphicsContext::setCurrentFill() function, and passing a pointer
		to a Fill instance. Keep in mind that the GraphicsContext does 
		<emphasis>not</emphasis> retain the pointer, instead it's the caller's 
		responsibility to free memory when they are through with the Fill.
		It's also a good idea to reset the GraphicsContext's fill to 
		NULL when you've deleted your Fill instance. It's perfectably 
		acceptable to have Fill instances allocated on the stack instead
		of using the heap. 
		</para>
		<para>
		The default fill implementation provided is the BasicFill class. It 
		supports anti-aliased rendering through AGG, and has several other
		settings that can be modified, such as the opacity and color.
		<note>
		Some settings only take effect if the drawing is taking place on a 
		GraphicsContext	that has anti-aliasing turned on.
		</note>
		Here's a simple example:
		<programlisting><![CDATA[
GraphicsContext* ctx = ....
BasicFill bf;
ctx->setCurrentFill( &bf );
BezierCurve shape;
shape.moveTo( 100, 100 );
shape.lineTo( 300, 300 );
shape.lineTo( 500, 300 );
ctx->draw( &shape );
ctx->setCurrentFill( NULL );
		]]></programlisting>
		
		</para>
		</section>
		<section id="Fill_Impl"><title>Implementation</title>
		<para>
		There are no set rules for how to implement the Fill interface.
		The primary function to implement is the Fill::render() function
		which will pass the stroke a Path instance. The Path will already 
		have been transformed by the GraphicsContext's transform matrix.
		</para>
		</section>	
	</section>
	
	<section id="ImageLoading"><title>Image Loading</title>
		<para>
		The VFC GraphicsKit supports loading of almost every image type.  Image loading is handled via 
		mime types.  The available image types are: PNG, JPEF, TIFF, KOALA, LBM, MNG, PCD, 
		PCX, PNM, PSD, RAS, and TARGA. On Win32 systems BMP is also supported. Image types
		other than BMP use the FreeImage library.
		</para>
					
		<para>
		In order to get access to the image loaders you must load the ImageFormats library.
		This library is available as a dynamic and static link version. Loading the 
		library as a dll on win32 platforms would be done as follows:
		</para>
		<programlisting>
<![CDATA[
#include "ImageFormatsSelectLib.h"

...

Library lib;
		
//load the library up. This library name can also be passed in to the
//constructor of the Library instance
//if the library doesn't exist or can't be found Library::load() will
//throw an exception
try {
	String libName = "ImageFormats_" + _LIB_CPLVERNUM;
	if( _DEBUG ){
		libName +="_d.lib";
	}
	else
		libName +=".lib";

	lib.load( libName );
		
}
catch(BasicException& e){
}
]]>
		</programlisting>
		<note>
		On Win32 systems, if all the files you want to load or save 
		are BMP files then the library need not be loaded. 
		</note> <!--JC: you don't need to do anything else - the Win32IMage peer
					takes care of laoding BMP images directly.-->
		<para>
		Once the lib is loaded, the ImageLoader for a mime type or
		for a file can be acessed from one of these methods in 
		GraphicToolit.
		</para>
<![CDATA[
ImageLoader* GraphicsToolkit::getImageLoader( const String& contentType )

ImageLoader* GraphicsToolkit::getImageLoaderForFileName( const String& fileName )
]]>
		<para>
		Now we have the ImageLoader for the file type or mime type. There
		are 3 methods in VFC::ImageLoader.
		</para>
		<para>
		The loadImageFromFile() method loads the file. All image types can
		be loaded. The signature of loadImageFromFile() is below:
		</para>
<![CDATA[
		Image* loadImageFromFile( const String& fileName )
]]>
		<para>
		Not all image formats can be saved.  The canSaveImage() method returns 
		true if save is supported and false if not. If it returns true and
		you need to save the image then call saveImageToFile() method.
		</para>
<![CDATA[
		void saveImageToFile( const String& fileName, Image* image )
]]>
		<note> 
		If saving is not supported and saveImageToFile is called no
		exceptions will be thrown.  The saveImageToFile methods will be empty
		in this case.
		</note>
	</section>
	
	
	<section id=""><title>Exceptions</title>
		<para>
		</para>
	</section>

	<section id=""><title>Peer Classes</title>
		<para>
		</para>
	</section>
</section>

<!--
CVS Log info
$Log$
Revision 1.5  2006/04/07 02:34:01  ddiego
initial checkin of merge from 0.6.9 dev branch.

Revision 1.4.2.4  2006/03/12 22:01:34  ddiego
doc updates.

Revision 1.4.2.3  2006/03/10 21:49:27  ddiego
updates to color example and some documentation.

Revision 1.4.2.2  2006/03/07 04:33:34  ddiego
more doc updates.

Revision 1.4.2.1  2006/03/02 22:13:01  ddiego
docs update.

Revision 1.4  2005/07/09 23:14:10  ddiego
merging in changes from devmain-0-6-7 branch.

Revision 1.3.4.1  2005/06/03 21:40:19  ddiego
more doc updates

Revision 1.3  2004/08/07 02:46:52  ddiego
merged in the devmain-0-6-5 branch to stable

Revision 1.2.4.2  2004/07/25 15:06:38  ddiego
added a few minor corrections.

Revision 1.2.4.1  2004/07/21 22:01:57  emonjay
Added loding images and completed dialog section minus graphics.

Revision 1.2  2003/12/18 05:15:52  ddiego
merge from devmain-0-6-2 branch into the stable branch

Revision 1.1.2.1  2003/09/24 19:41:18  ddiego
switched the sgml files over to xml file extensions
made a slight adjustment to the docbook makefile

Revision 1.2  2003/05/17 20:36:51  ddiego
this is the checkin for the 0.6.1 release - represents the merge over from
the devmain-0-6-0 branch plus a few minor bug fixes

Revision 1.1.2.5  2003/03/17 21:24:03  ddiego
blah

Revision 1.1.2.4  2003/03/13 02:34:40  ddiego
added some more docs and broke apart the various "books" so they can be all
put together or in separate books. Made to changes to Makefile

Revision 1.1.2.3  2003/03/10 03:58:34  ddiego
fixes ot better support online html, plus the addition of a little C++
program to stip stuff

Revision 1.1.2.2  2003/03/05 22:15:58  ddiego
more docs on images

Revision 1.1.2.1  2003/03/03 03:39:49  ddiego
initial check-in of docbook vcf documentation, plus neccesary stylsheets
and images

-->
