<!--
Copyright (c) 2000-2003, Jim Crafton
All rights reserved.
Redistribution and use in source and binary forms, with or without
modification, are permitted provided that the following conditions
are met:
	Redistributions of source code must retain the above copyright
	notice, this list of conditions and the following disclaimer.

	Redistributions in binary form must reproduce the above copyright
	notice, this list of conditions and the following disclaimer in 
	the documentation and/or other materials provided with the distribution.

THIS SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED BY THE COPYRIGHT HOLDERS AND CONTRIBUTORS "AS IS" 
AND ANY EXPRESS OR IMPLIED WARRANTIES, INCLUDING, BUT NOT
LIMITED TO, THE IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY AND FITNESS FOR
A PARTICULAR PURPOSE ARE DISCLAIMED.  IN NO EVENT SHALL THE REGENTS
OR CONTRIBUTORS BE LIABLE FOR ANY DIRECT, INDIRECT, INCIDENTAL, SPECIAL,
EXEMPLARY, OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES (INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO,
PROCUREMENT OF SUBSTITUTE GOODS OR SERVICES; LOSS OF USE, DATA, OR
PROFITS; OR BUSINESS INTERRUPTION) HOWEVER CAUSED AND ON ANY THEORY OF
LIABILITY, WHETHER IN CONTRACT, STRICT LIABILITY, OR TORT (INCLUDING
NEGLIGENCE OR OTHERWISE) ARISING IN ANY WAY OUT OF THE USE OF THIS 
SOFTWARE, EVEN IF ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH DAMAGE.

NB: This software will not save the world.


-->


<section><title>General</title>
	<qandaset>
		<qandaentry>
			<question>
				<para>Why are you writing another framework ? Aren't there enough out there ?</para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>
				The Visual Component Framework (VCF) was designed to make application 
				programming in general, particularly applications with User Interfaces, 
				much easier than it currently is with typical development tools. In addition 
				it was created to be cross platform in design, so a program relying only 
				on features within the VCF should simply recompile on another platform 
				supported by the VCF. In addition to all of this the VCF was designed to 
				support design time component editing, something that very few (Qt is the 
				only exception to this that I know of) toolkits/frameworks support. To 
				support this you need Reflection capabilities similar to what are found 
				in Java or Delphi, again very few C++ frameworks support this.
				</para>
			</answer>
			<question>
				<para>Regarding the copyright, is it open-source, gnu license, what are the rules
about that? I just saw the installer telling me you own the copyright, is that so?</para>
			</question>
			<answer>

				<para>The VCF license is a BSD license. The only restriction is that
				the copyright notice may not be stripped out from the source, and
				you need to give credit to the project and or author(s). Beyond
				that you are free to use the code however you like, and you are not
				<emphasis>required</emphasis> to release changes you make back to
				the VCF project (though they are certainly welcome to, and encouraged to 
				do so). Copyright is owned by the authors of the content.</para>
			</answer>
			<question>
				<para>How does  the VCF compare to other frameworks or toolkits,
					such as MFC, Qt, FLTK, FOX, and GTK?</para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para></para>
			</answer>

			<question>
				<para>Why not just help out an existing framework? Why write 
					yet <emphasis>another</emphasis> framework/toolkit?</para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>There are a variety of reasons, such as:
					<itemizedlist>
					<listitem>	<para>					
					One of the big ones is the dynamic nature of the 
					VCF due to the use of advanced RTTI features. For a number of frameworks this 
					would be difficult to fit in with out serious changes to the framework in question.
					</para></listitem>	
					<listitem>	<para>
					Another reason is simply the way the VCF is designed, for example the use of a Component
					base class for many of the UI controls, and the presence of Property and Component
					editors to support RAD design time editing. Supporting these requires certain features 
					that could be difficult to add in to an existing framework (this was partially the case 
					with wxWindows). 
					</para></listitem>	
					<listitem>	<para>
					Other issues are the usage of modern C++, such as templates, STL, namespaces, and exceptions. 
					These require a reasonably up to date C++ compiler (such as GCC, MS VC6 or VC7, 
					Borland C++, etc), and some of the existing toolkits place a high priority on supporting 
					older, non-standard	C++ compilers, which greatly reduces what features of the 
					C++ langauge are available to them.
					</para></listitem>	
					</itemizedlist>
				</para>
			</answer>
			<question>
				<para>Can we use the VCF in commercial applications?</para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>Yes. There are no restrictions made on how the VCF is 
				used. It can used in both OSS and commercial/proprietary 
				projects. In addition, due to the BSD license, you are free
				to make any changes to the VCF source code without obligations
				to share the changes. While people are encouraged to do so if
				possible, there is no requirement that forces this.
				</para>
			</answer>
			
			<question>
				<para>Is the VCF Documentation available in PDF format?</para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>Not currently, though there is an effort to make this 
				happen. </para>
			</answer>
			
			<question>
				<para>Is the VCF Documentation available in HTML for offline viewing?</para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>Yes, see the project downloads section and look for the
				Documentation area. </para>
			</answer>
			
			<question>
				<para>Is the VCF Documentation available as an HTML Help .CHM file?</para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>Yes, see the project downloads section and look for the
				Documentation area.</para>
			</answer>
			
			<question>
				<para>What would be required to port my MFC App to VCF?</para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>A miracle? Seriously porting an existing code in one framework to another
				is not a 5 minute job. It would partially depend on what features of MFC you make use of
				and how you built your app. Many of the function names are different or subtly different.
				The basic core concepts are pretty much the same, but the fundamental design of the two
				frameworks is quite different.
				</para>
			</answer>
			<question>
				<para>What platforms and/or compilers does the VCF support?</para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>Currently the VCF runs on Win32 (Windows 98, Windows NT 4 sp4 or better, Windows 2000
						and Windows XP). A linux port (with the UI/graphics parts based on GTK) is currently 
						underway and making good progress). Some work has been done on MacOSX, but it is 
						sporadic at best.</para>
				<para>
				As far as supported compilers, the VCF is known to compile/link with:
				<itemizedlist>
					<listitem>	<para>
					Microsoft Visual C++ 6 (sp5)
					</para></listitem>
					<listitem>	<para>
					Microsoft Visual C++ 7
					</para></listitem>
					<listitem>	<para>
					GCC 2.95
					</para></listitem>
					<listitem>	<para>
					GCC 3.2
					</para></listitem>
				</itemizedlist>						
				</para>
			</answer>
			<question>
				<para>How are the resources handled between OS's?</para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>On Win32 platforms resources are compiled into the executable using the toolchains rc compiler.
				For other platforms, the VCF will use whatever native support there is, or come up with an 
				appropriate scheme.</para>
			</answer>
			<question>
				<para>If a serious security/memory/whatever issue was found 18 months down 
				the track how is this handled? In general where do I go if I find bugs, and 
				if I do, how can I get them resolved?</para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para></para>
			</answer>
			<question>
				<para>How do I know what headers to use in my application? </para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>
				As a general rule you can do the following:	
				<itemizedlist>
					<listitem><para>
					If you're just using the FoundationKit, then you can 
					simply include the FoundationKit.h, i.e.
					<programlisting>
<![CDATA[					
#include "FoundationKit.h"					
]]>
					</programlisting>
					</para></listitem>
					<listitem><para>
					If you're just using the GraphicsKit, then you can 
					simply include the GraphicsKit.h, i.e.
					<programlisting>
<![CDATA[					
#include "GraphicsKit.h"					
]]>
					</programlisting>
					The GraphicsKit depends on the FoundationKit and will
					automatically include the FoundationKit header.
					</para></listitem>
					<listitem><para>
					If you're using the ApplicationKit, then you can 
					simply include the ApplicationKit.h, i.e.
					<programlisting>
<![CDATA[					
#include "ApplicationKit.h"					
]]>
					</programlisting>
					The ApplicationKit depends on the GraphicsKit and will
					automatically include the GraphicsKit header.
					</para></listitem>		
				</itemizedlist>
				
				</para>
			</answer>
			<question>
				<para>Why do I have to set environment variables?</para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>The VCF uses three environment variables to identify the following:
				<itemizedlist>
					<listitem>	<para>
					Where the vcf/include directory is (as an absolute path), stored as VCF_INCLUDE.
					This is the base include directory.
					</para></listitem>
					<listitem>	<para>
					Where the vcf/lib directory is (as an absolute path), stored as VCF_LIB.
					This is the base library directory.
					</para></listitem>
					<listitem>	<para>
					GCC 2.95
					</para></listitem>
					<listitem>	<para>
					GCC 3.2
					</para></listitem>
				</itemizedlist>
				</para>
			</answer>
			<question>
				<para>Will the VCF really save the world ?</para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>No, this is a cruel rumor started by an obviously deranged 
				individual. Probably someone who spends far, far too much time in 
				front of a computer...
				</para>
			</answer>			
		</qandaentry>
	</qandaset>
	</section>
	<section><title>Installation/Building the VCF</title>
	<qandaset>
		<qandaentry>
			<question>
				<para>Where the heck do I get this from ?</para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>
				You can get the VCF from the "Files" section at the Source Forge project page.
				Alternately you can also get the VCF from CVS, either in the current stable 
				release, or directly from the most recent (potentially <emphasis>unstable</emphasis>)
				development release.
				</para>
			</answer>
			<question>
				<para>Do I have to use CVS ?</para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>
				If you want to get the VCF sources from the CVS source tree, or be able to contribute 
				to the VCF as developer, yes. Otherwise you can get the source from the project's
				file downloads page, and submit patches for VCF devlopers to patch into the CVS tree.
				</para>
			</answer>
			<question>
				<para>What about SSH ?</para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>
				To use allow people to securely use CVS, Source Forge uses SSH. Most linux installations
				have this installed (as well as CVS), and Win32 users can get this set up and running 
				by downloading and installing <ulink url="http://www.cygwin.com">Cygwin</ulink>.
				</para>
			</answer>
			<question>
				<para>What other libraries do I need to get the VCF to run?</para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>
				This partly depends on the platform you use. For Win32 platforms the
				VCF has everything it needs in the source distribution. For Linux platforms
				you'll need GTK 2 (and whatever libraries that GTK requires).
				</para>
			</answer>
			<question>
				<para>What do I need to build ? Why do I have to build anything ? 
				Can't I just get the binaries ?</para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>For Win32 system's you can download the entire VCF including pre-built
				binaries, documentation, source, and MSDN integration all in one easy installer.
				As other platform ports become complete, similar installers will be made available.
				</para>
				<para>
				In terms of what parts of VCF you have build, this is partially dependant on how 
				you plan to use it. For console applications, it's likely that hte FoundationKit
				library is all you need. For GUI applications, you'll most likely want the 
				ApplicationKit, which in turn requires the GraphicsKit and FoundationKit libraries.
				</para>
			</answer>
			<question>
				<para>The documentation mentions a folder named "bin" which must be included 
				in the system path. I do not see any bin folder. Where is it?</para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>
				When you download the source code, the "bin" and "lib" directories
				do not exist. When you build the source code, these will be created 
				automatically as part of the build process. The "bin" directory holds
				the linked binary files (like .DLL/.so or .exe files) and the "lib"
				directory holds .lib or .a files. If you installed the VCF 
				through the installer, these directories will exist since the pre-built
				binaries will be installed there.
				</para>
			</answer>
			<question>
				<para>Using Visual C++ I get compiler errors complaining that it can't find certain 
				files. What do I do? </para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>
				Make sure that Visual C++ can find the vcf/include directory. This is what the 
				VCF_INCLUDE environment variable is for. An alternate solution (for Visual C++)
				is to add the vcf/include directory to the global list of include directories that
				Visual C++ searches through. To do this
				<itemizedlist>
					<listitem>	<para>
					Go to "Tools > Options..."
					</para></listitem>
					<listitem>	<para>
					Click on the "Options" tab.
					</para></listitem>
					<listitem>	<para>
					In the "Show Directories for:" drop down, select "Include files".
					</para></listitem>
					<listitem>	<para>
					Go to the end of the list, double click a blank item and add teh path to 
					wherever the vcf/include directory is found on your system.
					</para></listitem>
					<listitem>	<para>
					Click "OK" and you should be good to go.
					</para></listitem>
				</itemizedlist>
				</para>
			</answer>
			<question>
				<para>Using GCC I get compiler errors complaining that it can't find certain 
				files. What do I do?</para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>
				Ensure that the make file is correctly pointing to wherever the vcf/include
				is on your machine. If your building the VCF from the makefile, this shouldn't 
				be a problem. If you're having problems with building you own applications that 
				use the VCF, make sure you are including some thing like "-I $(VCF_INCLUDE)" in your
				make files.
				</para>
			</answer>				
			<question>
				<para>Using Visual C++ I get linker errors. What do I do? </para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>
				You probably do not have the vcf/lib directory in Visual C++'s lib path. 
				</para>
			</answer>				
			<question>
				<para>When I run my program (using Visual C++) I get weird crashes and memory 
				overwrites</para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>Make sure your code generation options match the VCF's (or any other 
				library you may link to). You should be using the "Multi Threaded DLL"
				or "Debug Multi Threaded DLL" (/MD or /MDd, respectively). If you don't do
				this, then memory that you allocate and delete will run into problems with 
				other libraries memory management.</para>
			</answer>				
			<question>
				<para>When I attempt to compile with Visual C++ 6, I get an Internal Compiler Error. 
				What do I do?</para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>Make sure that you have installed 
				<ulink url="http://msdn.microsoft.com/vstudio/downloads/updates/sp/vs6/sp5/dnldoverview.aspx">
				Service Pack 5</ulink> for Visual Studio C++. Also the Standard version of 
				Visual C++ seems to have some problems, so you'll need to use the Professional 
				or Enterprise version.
				</para>
			</answer>				
			<question>
				<para>I am using BoundsChecker, and it claims I have all sorts of memory leaks? 
					Is this really correct?</para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>
				Bounds Checker 6.x for Visual C++ tends to "quit" too early, and thus reports any 
				memory that it thinks is still allocated as "leaks", regardless if the memory is 
				freed by the application later on. This is a known bug, and affects other libraries
				that do their own memory reporting, and can safely be ignored. If you are in debug
				mode, and have the memory traps for VCF enabled (they are on by default), then
				any objects (that are directly or indirectly derived from VCF::Object) that have 
				not been freed are reported by the VCF.
				</para>
			</answer>				
			<question>
				<para>Can I use the VCF without writing a GUI?</para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>You most certainly can! Applications that do not need
				a user interface can simply link to the FoundationKit library.
				</para>
				<para>
				Should your application need graphics support (but not want or need
				any of the various GUI classes, such as controls, etc), it can link
				to the GraphicsKit library (this is in addition to the FoundationKit).
				</para>
			</answer>							
		</qandaentry>
	</qandaset>	
	</section>	
	<section><title>Contributing</title>
	<qandaset>
		<qandaentry>
			<question> 
				<para>Do I have to checkout all the code from sourceforge before 
					I can add  something?</para> 
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>You don't have to check it out. You can also send a patch. See the patch 
				submission page at the SourceForge project page 
				<ulink url="http://sourceforge.net/tracker/?group_id=6796&amp;atid=306796">here</ulink>
				</para>
			</answer>

			<question>
				<para>How do I joing the project?</para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>
				You must be a member of Source Forge (it's free), which you can do 
				<ulink url="http://sourceforge.net/account/register.php">here</ulink>. 
				Once you have joined the Source Forge, you can email the VCF Project admins
				and they can add you to the project.
				</para>
			</answer>

			<question>
				<para>Can I submit changes with out using CVS?</para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>Yes you can use the Patch system that can be found on the 
				 VCF's Source Forge project page.</para>
			</answer>
			
			<question>
				<para>Do you accept a patches? </para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>Yes, click <ulink url="http://sourceforge.net/tracker/?group_id=6796&amp;atid=306796">
				here</ulink> for more information. You must be logged in to Source Forge as a 
				registered Source Forge user before you can submit a new patch.
				</para>
			</answer>
		</qandaentry>
	</qandaset>			
	</section>
	<section><title>Libraries</title>
	<qandaset>
		<qandaentry>
			<question>
				<para>what is that Blackbox stuff?</para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>
				BlackBox is a Win32 DLL that can help track exceptions that happen at runtime,
				and can provide a stack trace that shows where the error occured. It is conceptually
				similar to the TalkBack module that Mozilla uses in their builds to handle error
				reporting.
				</para>
			</answer>
		</qandaentry>
	</qandaset>	
	</section>
	<section><title>Miscellaneous</title>
	<qandaset>
		<qandaentry>
			<question>
				<para>How do you document the source code?</para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>
				Source code documentation is done through comments in the source headers
				using <ulink url="http://java.sun.com/j2se/javadoc/writingdoccomments/index.html">
				Javadoc notation</ulink> (such as @author, @version, @return, @param, etc).				
				</para>
				<para>
				The documentation itself is produced by using 
				<ulink url="http://www.stack.nl/~dimitri/doxygen/">doxygen</ulink> 
				on all the source files.
				</para>
			</answer>
			<question>
				<para>What do you use to produce general documentation?</para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>
				The general documentation (which is what your reading right now) is produced
				by using <ulink url="http://docbook.sourceforge.net">docbook</ulink>.
				All the documentation is written in xml conforming to the docbook DTD. It is 
				then transformed by various docbook xsl stylesheets to produce the online 
				html and HTML Help files.
				</para>
			</answer>
			<question>
				<para>How can I edit and/or contribute to the VCF's documentation?</para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>
				The core documentation is located in a series of .xml files in the 
				vcf/docs directory. To add documentation to the VCF you should edit 
				these files. Please see the section on "Documentation Standards 
				and Generation" (section 1.6.4.2).
				</para>
			</answer>

			<question>
				<para>Is Doxygen free? Is it easy  to use like javadoc?</para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>Yes, Doxygen is free, and supports most of the basic javadoc tags 
				(which is why I use it).</para>
			</answer>			
			<question>
				<para>What is the VCF's performance relative to MFC?</para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>
				VCF performance is equivalent to MFC, and adds a noumber of "for free" features,
				like double buffering, and layout, that you typically have to write by hand
				in MFC. In addition the number of calls from when a native Win32 event is received
				to getting to an event handler within the framework is often much less, as MFC adds 
				a number of "extra" handling between the time the event is fired and is received 
				by the developers callback.
				</para>
			</answer>			
			<question>
				<para>What is the size/memory footprint difference of an 
				application written with VCF vs MFC?</para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>
				In terms of memory used by an application, the VCF uses more memory. For small
				utility applications, or size critical applications, this might make a difference,
				but for larger "desktop" applications, the difference becomes much less as the 
				application itself takes a lot of memory due to features and/or complexity
				regardless of using MFC or the VCF.
				</para>
				<para>
				The runtime binary libraries for the VCF are under 3MB in size (this includes
				the FoundationKit, GraphicsKit, and ApplicationKit).
				</para>
			</answer>			
			<question>
				<para>Is there a way to statically link to VCF rather then use the dlls? </para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>
				Yes, you can use the VCF as a static library.
				</para>
			</answer>						
			<question>
				<para>If I have written and application in MFC can I still use the VCF libraries in 
				this app? How hard/easy is it to integrate VCF code with other frameworks or vice-versa?
				</para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para></para>
			</answer>			
			<question>
				<para>How long will this project last? What happens in the original or current 
				developers lose interest? </para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para></para>
			</answer>
			<question>
				<para>Is the VCF help documentation integrated with the MSDN help for Visual Studio users?</para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>
				Yes, the win32 installer executable can integrate the VCF's documentation into 
				your MSDN collection.
				</para>
			</answer>
		</qandaentry>
	</qandaset>	
	</section>	
	<section><title>FoundationKit</title>
	<qandaset>
		<qandaentry>
			<question>
				<para>Does the VCF support XML?</para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>
				Yes. See the VCF::XMLParser class. The XMLParser class can handle
				basic xml files (it does not do any validation however). It can parse
				xml from a file name, or from string of xml text. Once parsed you can 
				access the xml document as an enumeration of XMLNodes. Alternately you
				can add event handlers to the XMLParser to get notified as it parses 
				the xml contents.
				</para>
				<para>
				An example of this looks like this:
				<programlisting>
<![CDATA[
VCF::XMLParser parser;
VCF::FileInputStream fs("path/to/some/file.xml");
parser.parse( &fs );
VCF::Enumerator<VCF::XMLNode*>* nodes =  parser.getParsedNodes();
while( nodes->hasMoreElements() ) {
	XMLNode* node = nodes->nextElement();
		if ( node->getName() == "foo" ) {
			XMLAttr* barAttr = node->getAttrByName( "bar" );
			String barVal = barAttr->getValue();
			String nodeCDATA = node->getCDATA();
		}
	}
}
]]>
				</programlisting>
				</para>
			</answer>
			<question>
				<para>What is the VCF::Interface good for?</para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>
				The VCF::Interface simply identifies a class as being an "interface". In 
				and of itself it has no functionality, other than to derve as a base 
				class for other interfaces.
				</para>
			</answer>
			<question>
				<para>How do I create a new thread ?</para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>
				You can create a thread by deriving a new class from VCF::Thread,
				and override the run() method. In your run() implementation you can 
				put whatever code you want to execute for your thread. To use the
				class you just create a new instance of it, call VCF::Thread::start(),
				and you're done. When your thread exits it's run() method, it will 
				delete itself. For more advanced usages, or to see how to further control
				the Thread behaviour (such as prevent auto deletion), see the VCF::Thread
				class documention.
				</para>	
				<para>
				A brief example looks like this:
				<programlisting>
<![CDATA[

bool canQuit = false;

class MyThread : public VCF::Thread {
public:
	virtual bool run() {
		int fooVal = 0;
		while ( fooVal < 1000 ) {
			fooVal ++;
			int calcVal = fooVal * sin(0.1234) - cos(0.78 * fooVal/(fooVal*2.0));
		}
		canQuit = true;
		return true;
	}
};

int main( int argc, char** argv ) 
{
	FoundationKit::init(argc,argv);
	Thread* thread = new MyThread();
	thread->start();

	while ( !canQuit ) {
		
	}

	FoundationKit::terminate();
	return 0;
}
]]>
				</programlisting>
				</para>
			</answer>
			<question>
				<para>How about Mutexs, Semaphores, etc ?</para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>
				Creating a mutex is easy:
<programlisting>
<![CDATA[
Mutex* m = new Mutex();
]]>
</programlisting>		
				To lock the mutex, simple call the Mutex::lock() method. If the lock() 
				fails it will return false. To unlock the mutex call the unlock method.
				For example:
<programlisting>
<![CDATA[
Mutex* m = getMyMutex();
m->lock();
String s = "Hello!";
myVectorOfStrings.push_back( s );
m->unlock();
]]>
</programlisting>		
				</para>
			</answer>
			<question>
				<para>Are the collections thread safe ?</para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>
				Collections are only as safe as the STL version that implements them. Please 
				check the documentation for the version of the STL that you're using 
				for more information about this.
				</para>
			</answer>
			<question>
				<para>How do I access a file ?</para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>
				If you want to read or write the contents of a file, use the 
				VCF::FileInputStream or VCF::FileOutputStream classes. If you want to 
				manipulate the file, for example copying it, or deleting it,
				use the VCF::File class.
				</para>
				<para>
				A quick example of reading from a file:
<programlisting>
<![CDATA[
FileInputStream fis("path/to/some/file.txt");
String fileText;
fis >> fileText;
]]>
</programlisting>
				A quick example of writing to a file:
<programlisting>
<![CDATA[
FileOutputStream fos("path/to/some/file.txt");
String fileText = "blah blah blah, yada, yada, yada";
fos << fileText;
]]>
</programlisting>	
				A quick example of copying and then deleting a file:
<programlisting>
<![CDATA[
File f("path/to/some/file.txt");
f.copyTo( "some/other/cool/path/file.txt" );
f.remove();
]]>
</programlisting>	
				</para>
			</answer>
			<question>
				<para>How do I change a files name ? </para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>
				Use the VCF::File class, and call the VCF::File::setName() method.
				A quick example of changing the name:
<programlisting>
<![CDATA[
File f("path/to/some/file.txt");
f.setName( "some/other/cool/path/file.txt" );
]]>
</programlisting>
				</para>
			</answer>
			<question>
				<para>Can I delete the file programmatically ? Does this actually delete the physical file on the hard disk ?</para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>
				Yes, use the VCF::File class, and call the VCF::File::remove() method. 
				Be careful as this will really delete the file!
				</para>
			</answer>
			<question>
				<para>Does the VCF support ref counting ?</para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>
				Yes. The VCF::Object class has methods for handling this. See 
				VCF::Object::addRef(), and VCF::Object::release().
				</para>
			</answer>
			<question>
				<para>Does the VCF support garbage collecting?</para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>
				No, at least not at this point. If you need garbage collector
				you'll have to implement this integration your self.
				</para>
			</answer>
			<question>
				<para>Does the VCF have a set of collection classes?</para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>
				Not really. The VCF makes heavy of STL which has an excellent set 
				of collection classes for virtually any use. What the VCF does provide
				is a simple enumeration class that <emphasis>wraps</emphasis> the 
				STL collection classes so you can get an enumeration back with being
				tied to the precise underlying collection implementation.
				</para>
			</answer>			
			<question>
				<para>Whats the point of the Object::destroy() and Object::free() methods</para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>
				In a typical C++ destructor it is not safe to call
				virtual methods, yet there are times when you need to do so. To 
				achieve this the VCF uses the Object::free() method to destroy all
				heap based instances. When Object::free() is called, it first calls
				Object::destroy(), and then deletes the instance. The Object::destroy() 
				is a virtual method that you can override in your own classes, and 
				provides a safe place to reclaim the object's resources and make
				virtual function calls. 
				</para>
			</answer>
			<question>
				<para>What is the "proper" or preferred way to delete an instance on the Heap?</para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>
				If the instance is derived (directly or indirectly) from VCF::Object, then
				the preferred way to delete the instance is to call the Object::free() member
				function. If the instance does not derive from VCF::Object then you can
				use the more traditional delete operator.
<programlisting>
<![CDATA[
class MyObject : public VCF::Object {
public:
	
};

class Stuff {

};

class MyObject2 : public MyObject {

};

int main( int argc, char** argv )
{
	Object* instance1 = new MyObject();
	MyObject2* instance2 = new MyObject2();
	Stuff* instance3 = new Stuff();

	//delete all the instances
	
	instance1->free();
	instance2->free();
	delete instance3;
}
]]>
</programlisting>
				</para>
			</answer>
			<question>
				<para>When should I create objects on the heap versus the stack in the VCF?</para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>
				As a general rule, you'll want to create most VCF based objects 
				on the heap, with the C++ new operator. All of the Component based
				classes should be create on the heap, with the exception of a modal
				Dialog. Some of the utility classes like Rect, Point, String, and Size can 
				be created on the stack.
				</para>
			</answer>
			<question>
				<para>What's the deal with the Enumerator class? I thought the VCF only used the STL for collections?</para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>
				The VCF::Enumerator class is simply a thin wrapper around an STL iterator.
				This provides a generic way to enumerate through a collection without having 
				to care or expose the actual collection implementation type.
				</para>
			</answer>
			<question>
				<para>Does the VCF support Unicode?</para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>
				Yes. All string handling is done using the UnicodeString class, which is typedeffed to 
				String. The String class is a thin wrapper around std::basic_string&lt;WideChar&gt; where
				WideChar is defined as an unsigned 16 bit type. For Win32, a single exe can run on either 
				Windows 9.x or WinNT and will use either the ansi versions of the API (Windows 9.x) or
				the Unicode versions of the API. This means you don't have to maintain separate builds
				for one platform or the other. Internally all string data is maintained in UTF16 format.
				</para>
			</answer>
			<question>
				<para>Does the VCF support i18n and l10n ?</para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>
				Yes. See the VCF::Locale class. You can change the locale, and by adding the proper resources
				to your application, provide localized string translation. 
				</para>
			</answer>
			<question>
				<para>How do I use the Input/Output streams?</para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>
				Input and Output streams are easy to use. You can determine the amount
				of data in the stream by calling getSize(). You can write to the stream 
				using the write() method, or write any basic type (int, char, double, 
				String) using the specialized write() method. You can write a buffer of
				data by passing in a const unsigned char pointer and a size. You can 
				read from an InputStream in similar fashion, using one of the read 
				functions.
				</para>
			</answer>
			<question>
				<para>How do I persist my objects data to a file?</para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>
				Well the easy way is to simply implement the Persistable interface, and 
				then just pass your object to a stream. For example:
<programlisting>
<![CDATA[
class MyObject : public VCF::Object, public VCF::Persistable {
public:
	virtual void saveToStream( VCF::OutputStream * stream ) {
		stream->write( myCount_ );
		stream->write( myName_ );
	}

	virtual void loadFromStream( VCF::InputStream * stream ) {
		stream->read( myCount_ );
		stream->read( myName_ );
	}
protected:
	int myCount_;
	String myName_;
};

int main( int argc, char** argv )
{
	FoundationKit::init(argc,argv);
	MyObject obj;
	
	FileOutputStream fso("path/to/my/file.txt");
	fso.write( &obj ); //or you could have written fso << &obj;
	fso.close();

	FileInputStream fsi("path/to/my/file.txt");
	fsi >> &obj;
	fsi.close();
	
	FoundationKit::terminate();
	return 0;
}
]]>
</programlisting>
				</para>
			</answer>
			<question>
				<para>How do I get at the command line arguments sent to my
						application (for example, if I wanted to know what file 
						to open)?</para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>
				Call FoundationKit::getCommandLine() which will return a CommandLine 
				object. See the documentation for the VCF::CommandLine class.
<programlisting>
<![CDATA[
CommandLine commandLine = FoundationKit::getCommandLine();
if ( commandLine.hasSwitch("-h") ) {
	//show usage listing...
}
]]>
</programlisting>

				</para>
			</answer>
			<question>
				<para>I got the VCF installed fine and my program compiled and 
						linked fine, but as soon as I run my application
						it crashes! What's wrong?</para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>
				You may not have initialized it correctly. If you have an app that makes 
				use of only the FoundationKit, then you have to initialize it like so:
<programlisting>
<![CDATA[
int main( int argc, char** argv )
{
	//initialize the FoundationKit
	VCF::FoundationKit::init(argc,argv);
	//your code here
	
	//close the FoundationKit down
	VCF::FoundationKit::terminate(); 
	return 0;
}
]]>
</programlisting>
				</para>
				<para>
				Likewise, if your application uses the GraphicsKit, then you need to 
				initialize the  GraphicsKit, by calling  GraphicsKit::init(argc,argv).
				Initializing the GraphicsKit automatically initializes the FoundationKit,
				and terminating the GraphicsKit also terminates the FoundationKit. 
				</para>
				<para>For applications that use a GUI the process is a little different.
				At the very least you need to create an Application instance (on the stack is OK),
				passing in the argc and argv arguments to the constructor, and then 
				call Application::main(). The initialization of the 
				ApplicationKit, GraphicsKit, and FoundationKit will be taken care of for 
				you. As an example:
<programlisting>
<![CDATA[
int main( int argc, char** argv )
{
	VCF::Application app( argc, argv );
	Application::main();	
	return 0;
}
]]>
</programlisting>
				</para>
			</answer>		
			<question>
				<para>Is there some kind of sprintf like routine in the VCF? 
						I can't seem to find anything and I really would like one!</para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>
				Yes, look in the StringUtils class for the static member function 
				VCF::StringUtils::format(). You can use like so:
<programlisting>
<![CDATA[
String formattedString = 
	StringUtils::format( "Hello from: %s at %d seconds to %0X4 at %.2f", "FooBar", 10, 124, 123.34788 );
]]>
</programlisting>
				</para>
			</answer>
<!--			
			<question>
				<para></para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>
				An answer.
				</para>
			</answer>
-->			
		</qandaentry>
	</qandaset>
	</section>
	<section><title>GraphicsKit</title>
	<qandaset>
		<qandaentry>
			<question>
				<para>How do I draw lines ? How do I draw thick lines ?</para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>
				Drawing lines is accomplished with the GraphicsContext::moveTo() and 
				GraphicsContext::lineTo() methods, and to render the lines to the screen,
				you call GraphicsContext::strokePath(). A quick example:
<programlisting>
<![CDATA[
GraphicsContext* gc = getMyGraphicsContext();//get the graphics context some how....
//draw a square
gc->moveTo( 0.0, 0.0 );
gc->lineTo( 100.0, 0.0 );
gc->lineTo( 100.0, 100.0 );
gc->lineTo( 0.0, 100.0 );
gc->lineTo( 0.0, 0.0 );

//render 
gc->strokePath();
]]>
</programlisting>
				</para>
				<para>Drawing with thick lines is also easy, just adjust the current
				stroke width of the GraphicsContext by calling GraphicsContext::setStrokeWidth(),
				for example:
<programlisting>
<![CDATA[
GraphicsContext* gc = getMyGraphicsContext();//get the graphics context some how....
//draw a square
gc->moveTo( 0.0, 0.0 );
gc->lineTo( 100.0, 0.0 );
gc->lineTo( 100.0, 100.0 );
gc->lineTo( 0.0, 100.0 );
gc->lineTo( 0.0, 0.0 );

//render 
gc->strokePath();

gc->setStrokeWidth( 10.0 );
//draw a thicker square
gc->moveTo( 200.0, 200.0 );
gc->lineTo( 300.0, 200.0 );
gc->lineTo( 300.0, 300.0 );
gc->lineTo( 200.0, 300.0 );
gc->lineTo( 200.0, 200.0 );

//render 
gc->strokePath();
]]>
</programlisting>
</para>
			</answer>
			<question>
				<para>How do I draw ellipses? Rectangles?</para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>
				To draw an ellips, use the GraphicsContext::ellipse 
				method. To draw a rectangle, use the GraphicsContext::rectangle()
				method.
<programlisting>
<![CDATA[
GraphicsContext* gc = getMyGraphicsContext();//get the graphics context some how....
gc->ellipse( 20, 20, 100, 100 );
gc->rectangle( 400, 400, 500, 600 );
gc->strokePath();
]]>
</programlisting>				
				</para>
			</answer>
			<question>
				<para>Is there any support for anti-aliased graphics?</para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>
				Yes, the VCF uses the <ulink url="http://www.antigrain.com/">
				AGG C++ graphics library</ulink> for 
				performing advanced anti-aliased vector graphics.
				</para>
			</answer>
			<question>
				<para>How do I use anti-aliased drawing?</para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>
				If you're drawing in a Control, then the simplest way is 
				to turn it on by calling Control::setUsingRenderBuffer(true),
				and then use the BasicStroke and BasicFill classes to draw
				with. You can see an example of this in the 
				vcf/examples/StrokesAndFills directory.
				</para>
			</answer>
			<question>
				<para>Is there an equivalent for the Win32 API call DrawEdge() ?</para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>
				Yes, you can call the GraphicsContext::drawEdge() method.
<programlisting>
<![CDATA[
GraphicsContext* gc = getMyGraphicsContext();//get the graphics context some how....
long edgeSides = GraphicsContext::etAllSides;
long edgeStyle = GraphicsContext::etSunken;
gc->drawEdge( &Rect(20,20,100,100), edgeSides, edgeStyle );
]]>
</programlisting>				
				</para>
			</answer>
			<question>
				<para>How do I change the color of a pen or brush ? Are there even pens or brushes ?</para>
			</question>
			<answer>
			<para>
			There are no Pen or Brush objects in the VCF. Instead you set the basic 
			attributes of a GraphicsContext object. For more advanced graphics features
			you would implement specific Stroke or Fill classes.
			</para>
			<para>
			To change the color that the GraphicsContext uses to fill or stroke a path
			you just need to call GraphicsContext::setColor() and pass in a pointer to 
			a color object. For example:
			<programlisting>
<![CDATA[
GraphicsContext* gc = getMyGraphicsContext();//get the graphics context some how....
gc->setColor( Color::getColor("red") );

gc->moveTo( 10, 10 );
gc->lineTo( 10, 100 );
gc->strokePath();
]]>			
			</programlisting>
			This will draw a straight vertical line, 90 pixels long, with the color
			red.
			</para>
			</answer>
			<question>
				<para>What's the deal with GraphicsContext::strokePath() and GraphicsContext::fillPath() methods?</para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>
				The GraphicsContext::strokePath() or GraphicsContext::fillPath() are used to
				either stroke, or fill the current path(s). A path is made using the GraphicsContext's
				moveTo(), lineTo(), curveTo(), 
				</para>
			</answer>
			<question>
				<para>How do I create an Image? Can I create one from a file? A resource?</para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>
				An answer.
				</para>
			</answer>
			<question>
				<para>How do I draw an Image ?</para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>
				An answer.
				</para>
			</answer>
			<question>
				<para>How do I modify Images ?</para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>
				An answer.
				</para>
			</answer>
			<question>
				<para>What's the Stroke class for? What about the Fill class?</para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>
				An answer.
				</para>
			</answer>
			<question>
				<para>How do I draw text?</para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>
				An answer.
				</para>
			</answer>
			<question>
				<para>How do I measure the length of some text I'd like to draw? What about the height?</para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>
				An answer.
				</para>
			</answer>
			<question>
				<para>How do I change the font that is used to render some text?</para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>
				An answer.
				</para>
			</answer>
			<question>
				<para>How do I change the color of text?</para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>
				An answer.
				</para>
			</answer>


		</qandaentry>
	</qandaset>
	</section>
	<section><title>ApplicationKit</title>
	<qandaset>
		<qandaentry>
			<question>
				<para>What kinds of controls(or widgets) are there in the 
				VCF?</para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>
				An answer.
				</para>
			</answer>
			<question>
				<para>How do I create a Timer ?</para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>
				An answer.
				</para>
			</answer>	
			<question>
				<para>What is the bare minimum necessary to create a new control ?</para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>
				An answer.
				</para>
			</answer>	
			<question>
				<para>What's the difference between a heavyweight and lightweight control ?</para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>
				An answer.
				</para>
			</answer>	
			<question>
				<para>How do I override events on my control ?</para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>
				An answer.
				</para>
			</answer>	
			<question>
				<para>How do I trap mouse events for my custom control ?</para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>
				An answer.
				</para>
			</answer>	
			<question>
				<para>What method do I override to draw or paint the control ?</para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>
				An answer.
				</para>
			</answer>	
			<question>
				<para>How do I make a window visible or show up?</para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>
				An answer.
				</para>
			</answer>	
			<question>
				<para>How do I close a window?</para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>
				An answer.
				</para>
			</answer>	
			<question>
				<para>How do I delete the memory for a Window or Dialog instance that I created ?</para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>
				An answer.
				</para>
			</answer>	
			<question>
				<para>Can existing controls be customized?</para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>
				An answer.
				</para>
			</answer>	
			<question>
				<para>How do add owner draw support to menu items?</para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>
				An answer.
				</para>

			</answer>
			<question>
				<para>Can I use threads in my GUI built with the ApplicationKit? If
					so what's the best way to do this?</para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>
				An answer.
				</para>
			</answer>
			<question>
				<para>Can I change the parent of a control at runtime?</para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>
				An answer.
				</para>
			</answer>
			<question>
				<para>How do I set the position of a Control? What about the
					width and/or height?</para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>
				An answer.
				</para>
			</answer>
			<question>
				<para>How do I add a context menu?</para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>
				An answer.
				</para>
			</answer>
			<question>
				<para>How can I send an event asynchronously to an event
						handler? Is there some equivalent to Window's PostMessage?</para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>
				An answer.
				</para>
			</answer>
			<question>
				<para>How do I add a menu bar and menu items?</para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>
				An answer.
				</para>
			</answer>
			<question>
				<para>How do I create and display a modal dialog?</para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>
				An answer.
				</para>
			</answer>
			<question>
				<para>How do I show a message in a modal dialog, such as an 
					error message?</para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>
				An answer.
				</para>
			</answer>
			<question>
				<para>How do I tell what the top level window it?</para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>
				An answer.
				</para>
			</answer>
			<question>
				<para>How to I get my control to refresh?</para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>
				An answer.
				</para>
			</answer>
			<question>
				<para>How do I make a control disabled (or enabled)? How do 
					I tell if it's already enabled?</para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>
				An answer.
				</para>
			</answer>
			<question>
				<para>How do I make a floating top level window apear with 
					no borders or caption/title bar (like a splash screen)?</para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>
				An answer.
				</para>
			</answer>
			<question>
				<para>How do I set the focus to a particular control? How do 
						I tell which control is currently focused?</para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>
				An answer.
				</para>
			</answer>
			<question>
				<para>How do I support drag and drop?</para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>
				An answer.
				</para>
			</answer>
			<question>
				<para>How do I change the cursor of a Control?</para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>
				An answer.
				</para>
			</answer>
			<question>
				<para>How do I add support for hot key combinations (like Ctrl+"C")?</para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>
				An answer.
				</para>
			</answer>
			<question>
				<para>How do I add scrolling support for a control?</para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>
				An answer.
				</para>
			</answer>
			<question>
				<para>Can I make my own cursor? If so how?</para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>
				An answer.
				</para>
			</answer>
			<question>
				<para>What's the difference bewteen a Component, Control,
						Frame, Dialog and Window?</para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>
				An answer.
				</para>
			</answer>
			<question>
				<para>How do I make a control keep all the mouse events? Is there
					something analgous to Win32's ::SetCapture GTK's gdk_pointer_grab()?</para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>
				An answer.
				</para>
			</answer>
		</qandaentry>
	</qandaset>
		<section><title>MVC</title>
		<qandaset>
			<qandaentry>
				<question>
					<para>How do I create a View?</para>
				</question>
				<answer>
					<para>
					An answer.
					</para>
				</answer>

				<question>
					<para>Does my custom View have to derive from VCF::Object?</para>
				</question>
				<answer>
					<para>
					An answer.
					</para>
				</answer>
				
				<question>
					<para>How do I add my view to a model?</para>
				</question>
				<answer>
					<para>
					An answer.
					</para>
				</answer>
				
				<question>
					<para>Where do I get the Model from?</para>
				</question>
				<answer>
					<para>
					An answer.
					</para>
				</answer>
				
				<question>
					<para>What kind of Model should I create?</para>
				</question>
				<answer>
					<para>
					An answer.
					</para>
				</answer>
				
				<question>
					<para>Are there default implementations to use when creating
					models or view? Is there a preferred model class to create or use
					or derive from? What about for a View?</para>
				</question>
				<answer>
					<para>
					An answer.
					</para>
				</answer>
				
				<question>
					<para>What are Items?</para>
				</question>
				<answer>
					<para>
					An answer.
					</para>
				</answer>
				
				<question>
					<para>Is an Item a View?</para>
				</question>
				<answer>
					<para>
					An answer.
					</para>
				</answer>
				
				<question>
					<para>Can a control have more than one View?</para>
				</question>
				<answer>
					<para>
					An answer.
					</para>
				</answer>
				
				<question>
					<para>Can a View have child views?</para>
				</question>
				<answer>
					<para>
					An answer.
					</para>
				</answer>
				
				<question>
					<para>How do I subscribe to a Model's change notification?</para>
				</question>
				<answer>
					<para>
					An answer.
					</para>
				</answer>
				
				<question>
					<para>Can I do this if I'm a View?</para>
				</question>
				<answer>
					<para>
					An answer.
					</para>
				</answer>
				
				<question>
					<para>I need to modify my model's data from multiple threads, 
					can I do this? What's the best way? Are there patterns to use?</para>
				</question>
				<answer>
					<para>
					An answer.
					</para>
				</answer>
			</qandaentry>
		</qandaset>
		</section>
	</section>
	
	<section><title>Component Authoring</title>
	<qandaset>
		<qandaentry>
			<question>
				<para>a question?</para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>
				An answer.
				</para>
			</answer>			
		</qandaentry>
	</qandaset>
	</section>	
	<section><title>NetworkKit</title>
	<qandaset>
		<qandaentry>
			<question>
				<para>a question?</para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>
				An answer.
				</para>
			</answer>			
		</qandaentry>
	</qandaset>
	</section>
	<section><title>RemoteObjectKit</title>
	<qandaset>
		<qandaentry>
			<question>
				<para>a question?</para>
			</question>
			<answer>
				<para>
				An answer.
				</para>
			</answer>			
		</qandaentry>
	</qandaset>
</section>


<!--
CVS Log info

$Log$
Revision 1.4  2004/12/03 03:06:01  ddiego
minor doc changes

Revision 1.3  2004/08/07 02:46:52  ddiego
merged in the devmain-0-6-5 branch to stable

Revision 1.2.4.2  2004/05/12 02:54:09  ddiego
updated mvc docs

Revision 1.2.4.1  2004/04/29 19:06:41  ddiego
added MVC example, plus the Model::changed() method. Also
added more documentation.

Revision 1.2  2003/12/18 05:15:52  ddiego
merge from devmain-0-6-2 branch into the stable branch

Revision 1.1.2.12  2003/12/01 03:44:12  ddiego
added some fixes to the Win32Toolbar impl. A few minor changes to the
toolbar example (which also got added). Some minor changes to docs
as well.

Revision 1.1.2.11  2003/11/10 22:17:36  ddiego
added some more updates to docs - finished off event section

Revision 1.1.2.10  2003/11/04 22:10:32  ddiego
*** empty log message ***

Revision 1.1.2.9  2003/11/03 22:21:01  ddiego
more faq documentation

Revision 1.1.2.8  2003/10/22 21:14:37  ddiego
adjusted the xsl stylesheet so it works with new version of xsltproc

Revision 1.1.2.7  2003/10/06 04:25:56  ddiego
updated foundationkit docs

Revision 1.1.2.6  2003/10/04 06:51:58  ddiego
answered more faq questions

Revision 1.1.2.5  2003/10/03 04:34:16  ddiego
added updates to FAQ

Revision 1.1.2.4  2003/10/03 01:45:29  ddiego
updates to faqs

Revision 1.1.2.3  2003/10/01 21:49:56  ddiego
*** empty log message ***

Revision 1.1.2.2  2003/10/01 04:34:52  ddiego
more faq editing

Revision 1.1.2.1  2003/10/01 01:57:27  ddiego
added the new faqs docs - all faqs i nthe document are now in one place
as opposed to being spread out over different chapters.

-->